

## **CONTACT ME**

**TEL:** +256 771 621 692

EMAIL: Wumpafrankajoel@gmail.com

LOCATION: Kampala, Uganda

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Proficient in Microsoft excel: am skillfully excellent in using vlookup, pivot tables and advanced if functions to generate reports.
- Proficient in Data Collection and Survey Tools: am skillfully excellent in designing and administering digital surveys using tools like KoboToolbox and Google Forms to gather accurate and reliable data.
- Skilled in Quantitative Data Analysis: am skillfully excellent in using statistical tools such as SPSS and Excel to analyze trends, test hypotheses, and generate evidence-based research findings.
- Proficient in Data Visualization: am skillfully excellent in creating dynamic dashboards and insightful charts using Excel and power BI to support data-driven decision-making.
- Experienced in Report Writing and Documentation: am skillfully excellent in synthesizing research data into clear, well-structured reports and policy briefs that inform program design and decision-making.

# **EDUCATION**

- Master's degree in monitoring and Evaluation- UTAMU/ MAY 2024- ON-GOING
- Bachelor's degree in Economics Kyambogo University / 2016-2019
- Uganda Advanced certificate of Education- Paul Mukasa SSS / 2014-2015

# WUMPA FRANK JOEL

DATA PROFESSIONAL

#### PROFILE SUMMARY -

A strong, self-motivated, results-driven data professional with a bachelor's degree in economics from Kyambogo University. Over four years of experience managing data and research-related roles, while obtaining data collection, analysis, and report generation skills. I seek a position that will allow me to utilize my current data skills and experience while offering opportunities for continued personal and professional growth.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE -

**Data Officer** / Makerere University Walter Reed Project OCTOBER 2023 - PRESENT, KAMPALA, UGANDA

- Successfully managed and maintained the accuracy and integrity of patient data within the Uganda medical records system (EMR), ensuring timely and accurate reporting to key stakeholders, including PEPFAR, MUWRP, and the Ministry of Health.
- Proactively analyzed and cleaned patient datasets, identifying and resolving data quality issues such as missing values and outliers to ensure timely submission of high-quality weekly, monthly, and quarterly reports.
- Collaborated effectively with healthcare workers to identify and address data gaps, develop strategies to meet facility targets, and streamline reporting processes for improved efficiency and data utilization.

**District-Based Trainer** / Youth Alive Uganda/MJAP APRIL 2022 - AUGUST 2023, LUUKA, UGANDA

- Collaborated with the District Health Officer (DHO) in the design and testing of robust survey instruments to effectively evaluate the impact of the Community Drug Dispensing Program
- Collaborated with the district Linkage officer to plan, implement, and report on peer support activities for people living with HIV (PLHIV), especially children, adolescents, and young people living with HIV (CALHIV).
- Facilitated M&E capacity-building mentorships and training sessions for project staff on HIV Prevention indicators, which improved their data collection and reporting skills

#### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS -

**Google** / Advanced Data Analytics Professional Certificate MAY 24 - NOV 2024, Coursera

NIDA Clinical Trials Network/Good Clinical Practice MARCH 2023

#### **REFERRES** -

Mwamula Daniel, Program officer, M&E

Makerere University Walter reed project, Email: <a href="mailto:Dmmwamula@muwrp.org">Dmmwamula@muwrp.org</a> **Muddooba David** District Programs Officer USAID LPHS-EC-MJAP

Email: Mudooba@mjap.mak.ac.ug